A Guide to the Ford Foundation records, International Affairs, Office of the Program Director, Office Files of Shepard Forman FA625
Rockefeller Archive Center
- Board of Trustees Meeting Materials, 1987-1994; II
  Series II, Board of Trustees Meeting Materials (1987-1994), is comprised of materials related to meeting logistics including schedule of events, seating plans as well as biographies of guest speakers, and outline of briefing books. The bulk of the materials consist of documents prepared by Foundation staff. These include site visit reports, program budget projections and proposed appropriations, recommended action items, papers presented at the meetings, and discussion papers used to generate dialogue on various topics which might affect future program directions. Papers on programs and study groups as well as information papers are part of this series. Memos documenting Trustees' suggestions are also included.
  - October 1987, 1987 October (Box 6 (SK #38318), Folder 1)
  - December 1987, 1987 December (Box 6 (SK #38318), Folder 2)
  - March 1989, 1989 March (Box 6 (SK #38318), Folder 3)
  - June 1989, 1989 June (Box 6 (SK #38318), Folder 4)
  - September 1989, 1989 September (Box 6 (SK #38318), Folder 5)
  - December 1989, 1989 December (Box 6 (SK #38318), Folder 6)
  - March 1990, 1990 March (Box 6 (SK #38318), Folder 7)
  - June 1990, 1990 June (Box 6 (SK #38318), Folder 8)
  - December 1990, 1990 December (Box 6 (SK #38318), Folder 9)
  - March 1991, 1991 March (Box 6 (SK #38318), Folder 10)
  - June 1991, 1991 June (Box 6 (SK #38318), Folder 11)
  - September 1991, 1991 September (Box 6 (SK #38318), Folder 12)
  - December 1991, 1991 December (Box 6 (SK #38318), Folder 13)
  - March 1992, 1992 March (Box 6 (SK #38318), Folder 14)
  - June 1992, 1992 June (Box 7 (SK #38676), Folder 1)
  - September 1992, 1992 September (Box 7 (SK #38676), Folder 2)
  - December 1992, 1992 December (Box 7 (SK #38676), Folder 3)
  - March 1993, 1993 March (Box 7 (SK #38676), Folder 4)
  - June 1993, 1993 June (Box 7 (SK #38676), Folder 5)
  - September 1993, 1993 September (Box 7 (SK #38676), Folder 6)
  - December 1993, 1993 December (Box 7 (SK #38676), Folder 7)
  - March 1994, 1994 March (Box 7 (SK #38676), Folder 8)
  - June 1994, 1994 June (Box 7 (SK #38676), Folder 9)
  - September 1994, 1994 September (Box 7 (SK #38676), Folder 10)
  - December 1994, 1994 December (Box 7 (SK #38676), Folder 11)
- Chronological Files, 1991-1993; III
  Series III, Chronological Files (1991-1993), is comprised of correspondence on a wide range of topics. The more mundane letters include requests to grantees for supplemental information, responses to inquires for funding outside the Ford Foundation scope, and requests for expense reimbursement. Letters with more substantial content include thoughts about candidates for Ford Foundation positions, responses to letters regarding programs, papers, or proposals that may influence program development within the Foundation, as well as requests to staff for input regarding proposals. There is some duplication in the Interoffice Memos series as well as Grant Files (i.e. program action reports, grant status reports). Sensitive materials include resumes.
  - June 1992, 1992 June (Box 8 (SK# 40166), Folder 1)
  - July 1992, 1992 July (Box 8 (SK# 40166), Folder 2)
  - August 1992, 1992 August (Box 8 (SK# 40166), Folder 3)
  - September 1992, 1992 September (Box 8 (SK# 40166), Folder 4)
  - January 1992, 1992 January (Box 9 (SK# 40167), Folder 1)
  - February 1992, 1992 February (Box 9 (SK# 40167), Folder 2)
  - March 1992, 1992 March (Box 9 (SK# 40167), Folder 3)
  - April 1992, 1992 April (Box 9 (SK# 40167), Folder 4)
  - May 1992, 1992 May (Box 9 (SK# 40167), Folder 5)
  - A-L 1991 (Box 10 (SK #38320), Folder 1)
  - M-Z 1991 (Box 10 (SK #38320), Folder 2)
  - A-L 1992 (Box 10 (SK #38320), Folder 3)
  - M-Z 1992 (Box 10 (SK #38320), Folder 4)
  - A-L 1993 (Box 11 (SK #38698), Folder 1)
  - M-Z 1993 (Box 11 (SK #38698), Folder 2)
- Interoffice Memoranda, 1991-1992; IV
  Series IV, Interoffice Memoranda (1991-1992), includes working papers, reports from conferences, interview-related materials, responses to consultant reports, presentation of program ideas, and more mundane memos regarding office facilities. Several folders are labeled - FF staff. FF staff is mainly the Ford Foundation's president, vice-president and Program staff.
  - IAP Staff - 1994 (July - December) (Box 12 (SK #38697), Folder 1)
  - SVB – Stockholm Visit (Box 12 (SK #38697), Folder 2)
  - 10th Floor - 1994 (Box 12 (SK #38697), Folder 3)
  - All other FF, 1994 (Box 12 (SK #38697), Folder 4)
  - All other FF, 1993 (Box 12 (SK #38697), Folder 5)
  - 10th Floor, 1993 (Box 12 (SK #38697), Folder 6)
  - IAP Staff, 1993 (Box 12 (SK #38697), Folder 7)
  - Other FF Staff Memos - 1992 (Box 13 (SK #38701), Folder 1)
  - 1992 Tenth Floor (Box 13 (SK #38701), Folder 2)
  - G&PP Staff Memos - 1992 (Box 13 (SK #38701), Folder 3)
  - IAP Staff Memos - 1992 (Box 13 (SK #38701), Folder 4)
  - M. Picken – Poland Trip Notes (Box 13 (SK #38701), Folder 5)
  - 1991 FF Staff Memos to SF (July – December), 1991 July - December (Box 13 (SK #38701), Folder 6)
  - 1991 FF Staff Memos to SF (January – June), 1991 January - June (Box 13 (SK #38701), Folder 7)
  - IAP Staff Memos, 1994 (Box 14 (SK #39577), Folder 1)
  - IAP Staff Memos, 1995 (Box 14 (SK #39577), Folder 2)
  - 10th Floor Memos, 1995 (Box 14 (SK #39577), Folder 3)
  - All Other FF Memos, 1995 (Box 14 (SK #39577), Folder 4)
  - 10th Floor Memos, 1996 (Box 14 (SK #39577), Folder 5)
  - All Other FF Memos, 1996 (Box 14 (SK #39577), Folder 6)
- Trip Files, 1990-1995; V
  Series V, Trip Files (1990-1995), mainly consists of itineraries, reading materials for meetings, agenda, handwritten notes, and lists of participants. Also included in a smaller amount are meeting proceedings, lists of grants, and strategy papers.
  - Vienna/Slovakia, 1995 December (Box 15 (SK #38677), Folder 1)
  - McArthur Foundation Meeting, 1995 October 19 (Box 15 (SK #38677), Folder 2)
  - Copenhagen, 1995 March 6 - 11 (Box 15 (SK #38677), Folder 3)
  - Russia Trip (Box 15 (SK #38677), Folder 4)
  - San Francisco, 1995 June 20 - 25 (Box 15 (SK #38677), Folder 5)
  - San Francisco, 1995 May 2 - 4 (Box 15 (SK #38677), Folder 6)
  - Cophenhagen (World Summit on Social Development), 1995 March 8 - 11 (Box 15 (SK #38677), Folder 7)
  - Washington, D.C., 1995 March 3 - 4 (Box 15 (SK #38677), Folder 8)
  - Potantica (IEW Retreat), 1995 November 18 - 20 (Box 15 (SK #38677), Folder 9)
  - Kiev/Moscow, 1994 October 12 - 26 (Box 15 (SK #38677), Folder 10)
  - Quebec City (Aspen Institute), 1994 August 14 - 19 (Box 15 (SK #38677), Folder 11)
  - Washington, D.C. (Bretton Woods), 1994 July 20 - 21 (Box 15 (SK #38677), Folder 12)
  - Istanbul (Muslim Meeting), 1994 June 11 - 16 (Box 15 (SK #38677), Folder 13)
  - Poland, Geneva, Switzerland, 1994 April 19 - 29 (Box 15 (SK #38677), Folder 14)
  - Aspen Institute, 1994 April 4 - 9 (Box 15 (SK #38677), Folder 15)
  - McArthur Foundation, 1994 January 24 (Box 15 (SK #38677), Folder 16)
  - Costa Rica (Retreat), 1994 February 21 - 25 (Box 15 (SK #38677), Folder 17)
  - Washington, D.C., 1994 October 21 - 22 (Box 15 (SK #38677), Folder 18)
  - Moscow/Prague, 1993 July (Box 15 (SK #38677), Folder 19)
  - Moscow, 1993 June 9 - 18 (Box 15 (SK #38677), Folder 20)
  - Warsaw/Slovenia, 1993 May 16 - 23 (Box 15 (SK #38677), Folder 21)
  - Washington, D.C., 1993 May 3 (Box 15 (SK #38677), Folder 22)
  - Prague/Moscow, 1993 April 12 - 23 (Box 15 (SK #38677), Folder 23)
  - Moscow, 1993 January 28 (Box 15 (SK #38677), Folder 24)
  - Washington, D.C., 1993 March 18 - 19 (Box 15 (SK #38677), Folder 25)
  - Little Rock, 1993 January 7 - 8 (Box 15 (SK #38677), Folder 26)
  - Washington, D.C., 1992 December 13 - 14 (Box 15 (SK #38677), Folder 27)
  - Washington, D.C., 1990 October 4 (Box 16 (SK #38678), Folder 1)
  - Lagos, Nigeria: Africa Governance, 1990 October 27 - 28 (Box 16 (SK #38678), Folder 2)
  - Vienna/Prague/Warsaw, 1991 April (Box 16 (SK #38678), Folder 3)
  - Providence, RI, 1991 May 24 (Box 16 (SK #38678), Folder 4)
  - Strasbaurg, 1991 May 22 - 25 (Box 16 (SK #38678), Folder 5)
  - London, 1991 June 1 - 7 (Box 16 (SK #38678), Folder 6)
  - Boston Trip, 1991 September 24 (Box 16 (SK #38678), Folder 7)
  - Washington, D.C., 1991 October 3 - 4 (Box 16 (SK #38678), Folder 8)
  - Washington, D.C., 1991 October 24 (Box 16 (SK #38678), Folder 9)
  - Vilnis/Moscow/Vienna, 1991 November 2 - 18 (Box 16 (SK #38678), Folder 10)
  - Africa: Program Meeting, 1992 January 20 - 24 (Box 16 (SK #38678), Folder 11)
  - Washington, D.C., 1992 February 27 - 28 (Box 16 (SK #38678), Folder 12)
  - New Dehli/Beijing, 1992 March 1 - 31 (Box 16 (SK #38678), Folder 13)
  - Washington, D.C. – Eagleburger, 1992 March 31 (Box 16 (SK #38678), Folder 14)
  - Brown University, 1992 April 8 (Box 16 (SK #38678), Folder 15)
  - Washington, D.C., 1992 April 10 (Box 16 (SK #38678), Folder 16)
  - Cambridge, MA, 1992 April 15 (Box 16 (SK #38678), Folder 17)
  - New York: Arden House, 1992 June 26 - 28 (Box 16 (SK #38678), Folder 18)
  - Moscow, Warsaw, 1992 July 13 - 24 (Box 16 (SK #38678), Folder 19)
  - Vienna: Aspen Institute, 1992 August 23 - 28 (Box 16 (SK #38678), Folder 20)